# Ahmed Khaled A. Awwad

SOC Analyst Tier 1

in Ahmed Awwad 🔘 Blog 📞 +201117753991 💌 a.k.awad97@gmail.com 🥃 Military due date: 1/6/2024

Electronics and Communication Engineer, Jr SOC analyst 1 year experienced in analysis and cooperate in incident investigations. Self-learner, Self-motivated and pursued my goals to build oriented career also enhancing my skills in Cybersecurity knowledge in all domains continuously.

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

CTFs writeups, Awwad's Blog ☑

Cybertalents,

Top 200 in Egypt rank. ☑

**Foundations of Operation MITRE** ATT&CK, ATTACKIQ Academy 🖸

Cisco CCNAv7 🛮

Introduction to Networks Switching, Routing, and Wireless Essentials Enterprise Networking, Security, and Automation

## **SKILLS**

**SIEM Solutions | EDR | SOAR** 

**Incidents Investigation** 

**Infrastructure & System Security** 

**Application & Network Security** 

Linux | Cryptography | R&D

**Network & Systems administration** 

**Programming** 

Python, Bash, C++..

**Technical Reporting/Writing** 

#### **LANGUAGES**

Arabic

Mother tongue

**English** 

**B2-Upper Intermediate** 

## **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor of Communication and Electronics Engineering,**

Faculty of Engineering Helwan University

Project: Email Anti-spammer system 🛮

Degree: Excellent

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Armed Forces**

Kaspersky Administrator

Jul 2023 | Confidential

Serving as Kaspersky administrator. Monitor, Maintain and develop Kaspersky server and managed devices.

Network and System Administrator

Jul 2023 | Confidential

Serving as a Network and computer systems administrator. Manage all military internal networks, systems, install, configure, and maintain organizations' computers.

#### **Optima Professional Services (OPS)**

SOC Analyst

Jul 2023 - 2024 | Part time

SOC Analyst | Tier 1

Oct 2022 - May 2023 | Full time

Monitor and manage all information security incidents. Follow-up with the IT Teams and other Business Units to develop action plans to mitigate identified vulnerabilities.

**Excel Codes,** Back-end Developer intern □

Sep 2017 – Dec 2017

"ICenna " Website and Mobile Application Back-End Developer for Python (Django) for websites and applications.

Freelancer, Curriculum writer

Aug 2017 - Jan 2019

Physics & Mathematics content writer, booklets content designing and translating Arabic content to English

## **PROJECTS**

#### **Spamurai,** Graduation project

Spamurai is Email Anti-spammer system in cyber security field. It is Research and development (R&D) project aim to find and implement a solution to detect and prevent or lessen the interaction of users with any adware, harmful/spam emails based on content analysis as URL, TEXT and Files.

## Auxilio Robotic, IEEE RAS, Certificate 🗷

**IEEE Helwan Student Chapter** 

I was assigned to lead control team & code via Arduino.

Our objective is to structure Line follower Robot help disabled people by carrying different objects with controllable arm and following the line path to a certain destination automatically or manually through an application to control direction and movement.

## **COURSES & INTERNSHIPS**

## **CCNAv7**, National Telecommunication Institute (NTI)

Oct 2022 - Dec 2022

Network fundamentals, network access, IP connectivity & services, Network security fundamentals, and laying the foundation for network automation and programmability.

Certificates

## **Cyber Security Engineer,** *Udacity*

Jul 2022 - Nov 2022

Nanodegree Expert level program by egFWD ITIDA  $\ \ \, \square \ \,$ 

- Security Engineering Fundamentals
- System Security
- Infrastructure Security
- Application Security

Nanodegree Certificate 🛮

## **Cyber Security Engineer Intern,** *VTF* □

May 2022 - Jul 2022 | Online

Cyber Security Teams and their roles. Gained knowledge in Splunk, Mitre Att&ck, OSINT, Pfsense, Cloud and Presenting skills.

Certificate 🗷

#### **Pentester trainee,** Trend Micro & CyberTalents

Jun 2021 – Aug 2021

Penetration Testing cycle and phases. Dived deep into OWASP top 10 vulnerabilities.

Achieved top 10 in the evaluation CTF.

Certificate 🗷

### **Full Stack Web Developer,** *Udacity*

Feb 2018 - May 2018 | Online

- "One Million Arab Coder" in Full-Stack Web Developer.
- Python Language
- Version control: Git GitHub

Certificate 🗷

## Front-End Web Developer, Udacity

Nov 2017 – Feb 2018 | Online

"Google Developer Challenge" in Front-End Web.